PETER BENVENUTO

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

EXPERIENCE

Senior Product Designer | Mozilla

MAY 2021 - PRESENT, TORONTO, ON

- Owned design and strategy for our core global VPN product helping to increase MRR to ~90% (\$334k to \$656k)
- Led design discovery and execution of all major features which grew our subscribers from 50k active subs to 127k active subs in 30 countries
- Led initiative to improve the conversion funnel which, despite the fact that our customer base grew YoY, support tickets related to login dropped ~60% and conversion improved ~50%
- Led org-wide design system audit, rebuild and maintenance that was used by 4 products

Product Designer | Intrado

MAR 2021 - MAY 2021, TORONTO, ON

- Led the org-wide design audit and the creation of internal design system within 3 months
- As the sole designer I was responsible for design strategy, research and execution of 5 major features of our core SaaS product
- Championed accessibility and led org-wide accessibility audit of our marketing sites and core SaaS product

Software Engineer | InvestCloud Inc.

SEP 2018 - MAR 2021, BURLINGTON, ON

- Developed and shipped financial portals for 4 main clients, using HTML,
 CSS and JavaScript
- Design RESTful web APIs to seamlessly extract client data from existing CRM systems

MENTORING & TEACHING

Front End Development Tutor | CareerFoundry

FEB 2022 - PRESENT, REMOTE

UX Mentor & Instructor | BrainStation

NOV 2022 - PRESENT, TORONTO, ON

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, User Experience Design

SEP 2020 - DEC 2020, TORONTO, ON

York University | Bachelors, Political Science

SEP 2011 - 2014, TORONTO, ON

peterbenvenuto90@gmail.com 416-456-3019 linkedin.com/in/peter-benvenuto github.com/PeterBen90 peterbenvenuto.com

PROFILE

I'm a product designer and overall creative technologist with over 6 years of experience across disciplines. I started my career as a software engineer where I was building products for over 3 years, fast forward to now, where I enjoy being the brains behind what we build to help solve problems for users. I'm passionate about storytelling, crafting beautiful experiences, scaling design systems, and shoes.

DESIGN SKILLS

Information architecture, Wireframing, UI prototyping, Interaction design, Motion design, Responsive design, Design systems, Visual design, User research and testing, Figma, Sketch, InVision, InVision Studio, Zeplin, Zeroheight, Adobe Creative Suite

DEV SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Redux, Material UI, Bootstrap, Bulma, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Java, Groovy, PostgreSQL, SQL, Git, Responsive design

CERTIFICATIONS

Software Engineering - Thinkful Enterprise Design Thinking - IBM Marketing - Humber College